Guide to the Kenneth Walter Cameron Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1794-1977, undated; Accession 1994-M-030; 23 linear feet (28 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1994 Jan
  Received fom: Kenneth W. Cameron, 1993 Oct 18
  - Franklin Benjamin Sanborn (1831-1917)
    - Bibliography, life, literary writings in chronological order (Box 1–5)
    - Bibliography (Trinity Library holdings) (Box 6–8)
    - Correspondence, 1850-1917 (Box 6–8)
    - Poetry, 1840-1915 (Box 6–8)
    - Letters to FBS from David Atwood Wasson: microfilm, 1857-1868 (Box 8–9)
    - Sanborn letters -Clarkson's (Box 8–9)
    - Concord School of Philosophy and Literature (and its successors): founded by Emerson, Alcott, and Sanborn, "News Reports from the Beginning", 1879-1920 (Box 8–9)
    - Scrapbooks of clippings on John Brown and Kansas Civil War: microfilm (Box 10–11)
  - Lyceum Records, Massachusetts: Parts I, II, 1830-1870 (Box 10–11)
  - Correspondence of William Cullen Bryant (1794-1878) (Emerson's favorite American poet) (Box 10–11)
  - Newspaper clippings from the diary of Amos Bronson Alcott (1799-1888) (Box 12)
  - Henry David Thoreau (1817-1862): Records of his intellectual life (Box 13–16)
  - Ralph Waldo Emerson (1803-1882)
    - Sermons, early lectures (Box 17)
    - Film (Sanborn) -Boston Commonwealth (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous: filmstrips, microfilm (Box 17)
  - American Writers of the 19th Century
    - Chronological file (Box 18–20)
    - Background/topical files (Box 18–20)
  - Oversize materials (primarily photocopies)
    - Sanborn's scrapbooks of newspaper clippings on John Brown and slavery, 1800s (Box 21)
    - "Thoreau's Literary Note-book: selections of Thoreau's favorite literary specimens, also some original verses by Thoreau" (Box 22)
    - Thoreau's Harvard College Notebook, 1835 (Box 22)
    - "Original Mss and Letters of Henry D. Thoreau with the Merrimack Map Drawn by Himself", undated (Box 22)
  - Thoreau's journal, "Miscellaneous/Holograph Notes", 1836 November 12-[1840?], 1859 (Box 23)
  - "A Walk to Wachusett", undated (Box 23)
  - "A Week on the Concord and Merrimac Rivers", undated (Box 23)
  - "Bronson Alcott's English Friends," by William Harry Horland, 1907 (Box 23)
  - Newspaper clippings relating to Emerson, Thoreau, and Concord, 1820s, 1882, 1903, undated (Box 23)
  - Professor Edward Tyrrell Channing's theme assignments, Harvard University, 1822-1852 (Box 23)
  - Concord School of Philosophy and Literature, 1880s (Box 24)
  - "College Papers, Translations of George Moore, 1828 December 17-1829 April 1 (Box 25)
  - "A Journal of a Country school Master, While Keeping a School in Acton, Mass," by George Moore, 1836 August 3 1846 December 27 (Box 26)
  - Library of the Reverend Convers Francis, 1800s
    - "Theological School in Cambridge -Catalogue of the Francis Library" (Box 27)
  - College Notebooks of the American poet Jones Very, 1830s (Box 27)
  - Microfilm
    - Thoreau Fact Book at Harvard (Box 27)
    - George Moore's themes and papers (Box 27)
    - Thoreau's "Paragraphs Mostly Original" (Box 27)
    - Letters of William Cullen Bryant in Boston Public Library (Box 27)
    - Washington Irving despatches (3 reels) (Box 27)
    - Nathaniel Hawthorne despatches (3 reels) (Box 27)
  - The Willow Motif in English Literature and Life from 1500 Until the Present, by Kenneth Walter Cameron: prospectus and research, undated (Box 28)
  - Chanutus, Stephanus, Regimen Castitatus conservatin arbori ludaice iunctu: filmstrip (Box 28)
  - An Illustrated History of the Herbals, by Frank J. Anderson, 1977 (Box 28)
  - The Old English Herbals, by E.S. Rohde, 1922 (Box 28)
- Additional material, Accession 1996-M-119
  - Subject files [primarily printed material]
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo (Box 1–4)
    - Thoreau, Henry David (Box 5–8)
    - Nineteenth century American literary renaissance (Box 9–21)
- Additional material, Accession 2000-M-101
  - The Cameron Collection [bound annotated typescripts], undated
    - "Emerson's Sermons," vols. I-IV (Box 1)
    - "Index-Concordance to Emerson's Sermons" (Box 1)
    - "Extracts From the Early Journals of Emerson with My Indexes" (Box 2)
  - Printed material by/or edited by Kenneth W. Cameron [topics include Anglicanism, Loyalists, American authors], 1973-1997 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous publications [primarily catalogs], 1930s-1980s (Box 3)
- Additional material, Accession 2000-M-102
  - The Record, Wheeling High School, Wheeling, West Virginia, 1926 (Box 1)